Rachel Beyerlein

UX / UI Designer

Senior Designer with a background in graphic design, CPG packaging, environmental signage, and project management. 10+ years experience tackling the needs of international companies. Able to deliver quality work under tight deadlines in fast-paced environments, with a keen focus on research and organization.

based in Montréal, Quebec rachelbeyerlein@gmail.com +1 438.923.3422

Experience

03.2022 - current UX/UI Design Student

User Experience Design program that includes 500+ hours of professional training, focusing on user-centered design methods and design thinking skills. Portfolio of student work includes: Foreign language learning native app, Healthcare Mobile-first website development.

01.2021 - current Self-Employed / Freelance

Branding & Packaging Design, Montreal, Canada

Design and conceptualize branding and packaging solutions for clients with a focus on community involvement: École NDG, Notre Dame des Arts.

09.2021 - current Social Media Content Manager / Co-Host

Ladies, Wine & Design Montreal, Montreal, Canada

Assist run the local chapter of global non-profit organization to empower female designers, encourage diversity, and promote female leadership.

02.2020 -09.2020 Senior Designer

Pahnke Markenmacherei, Hamburg, Germany

Head of USA and Canadian packaging design division. Harmonized and expanded Storck chocolate and sweets product lines, specifically Werther's Originals, Toffifay, merci.

09.2018 -09.2020 Host & Lead-Coordinator

CreativeMornings Hamburg, Hamburg, Germany

Enabled Creatives to collaborate in meaningful ways by re-introducing the community to the power of gathering. Responsible for building partner relationships, developing targeted communication channels, writing and organizing social media and event marketing strategies.

06.2012 -12.2019 Packaging and Corporate Designer

Peter Schmidt Group (BBDO network), Hamburg, Germany

Led visual development of graphic solutions for global brands in hospitality, gastronomy and CPG segments. Competencies include packaging design, logos, branding, and systems development.

09.2009 -09.2011 Graphic Designer

skydesign graphics, Atlanta, GA

Designed and executed visual solutions including: branding systems, environmental graphics development, logo development, and marketing for hospitality, retail, civic and private corporations.

06.2008 - 12.2008 Design Intern in Global Licensing

The Coca Cola Company, Atlanta, GA

Prepared graphics standards for apparel and assisted with photo-correcting archival images.

Education

UX Design Immersion

CareerFoundry 03.2022 - 12.2022 (expected)

Graphic Design

The Portfolio Center Atlanta, Georgia 2007 - 2009

BA English Lit, minor: French

The University of Michigan Ann Arbor, Michigan 2002 - 2006

Digital Skills

Figma

Adobe CC: Illustrator, Indesign,
Photoshop, Acrobat
MS Office: Word, Excel, Outlook,
Powerpoint
Photography: Retouching
Trello, Slack
Mailchimp

Clients

G-Suite

Jim Beam, Henkel EU & USA, pwc, YMCA of the USA, Beyersdorf, Werther's Original, merci, Penny Markt, Rewe Supermarkets, Costa Meeresspezialitäten, Chick-Fil-A, World Financial Center

Language Skills

English, Deutsch, Français

References available upon request